Now that we've talked about what an
object is, how do we create one? Well,
if we want to create an array, we say,
"Let my array equal
and then we use square braces." So to
differentiate objects from arrays, we
actually use a similar but slightly
different syntax. So we'd say let my
object equal and then we'd use curly
braces.
So this is an this is an array. This is
an object. Okay. Well, how do we put
something in an object? Well, I'm going
to give this object a name. And I'm
gonna call this object Batman. And I'm
going to create um remember just like a
dictionary, it has a a word and an
associated definition. So, in this case,
I'm going to put first name and then a
colon and then on the other side of it,
I'm going to put Batman. What that does
is it says create a bat an object, store
it in a variable called Batman. that
object will have a property called first
name. When someone tries to access that,
give them Batman.
All right, then we'll keep going. Um, so
we'll say last name Whoa, sorry, I don't
know what I said. First name Bruce, last
name Wayne.
um alias
Batman
and then I could say numbum villains
caught and 20.
So what I've done is I've made an object
in that object it has values and sorry
it has definitions and those definitions
have values. So just like I could look
up in my dictionary and find a word and
it'll give me back the definition. I can
look things up in this object.
So if I want to alert Batman's first
name, then I would access my variable
Batman say dot and then I have these
properties here. So I could say
Batman.irstame.
If I save this and I go live, I get
Bruce. If I come back over here and I
access Batman.ast name, save it. and it
says Wayne.
So the reason this is nice is because
then we can access attributes by their
names.
Another way we can do this is we can say
Batman and then use the square braces
just like we did with an array and then
we'll put in the text alias
and we get Batman. So there's two ways
you can access an attribute on an
object. You can say Batman square braces
and then the attribute or you can say
Batman dot and then the attribute. So
you take whatever variable you have, use
square braces and access it using quotes
around the name or you can just say dot
and then directly access the name. So
that's how you access attributes in an
object. So why is this nice? Well,
um let's bring in our Batman list. So
I'm going to go copy it from here.
and I'm going to paste it.
So, we'll call this Batman 2.
All right. So if we want to do um array
dstructuring so that we can access these
by names then we might say let first
last alias
num villains
equal Batman 2. What that does is it
takes Bruce puts it in first, Wayne puts
it in last, Batman puts it in alias and
20 and puts it in number of villains.
The problem becomes when there's a data
entry error and Wayne is actually
swapped places with Batman.
Oops.
Now, this destructuring is going to take
Bruce and put it in first, which works,
but it's going to put Batman in last.
And his last name is not Batman. His
last name is Wayne. Um, with an object,
Bruce is firmly tied to first name,
which means when we access Batman. first
name, it will always be Bruce.